A Finding Aid to the E. P. (Edgar Preston) and Constance Richardson papers, 1814-1996, bulk 1921-1996, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
E.P. (Edgar Preston) and Constance Richardson papers
1814-1996
bulk 1921-1996
Archives of American Art
Richardson, Edgar Preston, 1902-1985
Richardson, Constance, 1905-
AAA.richedga
Archival Resource Key
28.7 Linear feet
The papers of art historian E. P. Richardson measure 28.7 linear feet and date from 1814-1996, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1921-1996. Within the papers are scattered biographical materials; acquisition files for Richardson's personal art collection; professional and personal correspondence with colleagues, art historians and critics, artists, museums, galleries, and dealers; numerous writings, including manuscripts and research files for his published books, articles, and lectures; general research notebooks and files compiled by Richardson on a wide variety of art-related topics and artists; professional and committee files; as well as a smaller amount of Constance C. Richardson's papers.
Biographical / Historical
Art historian, museum director, and writer E. P. (Edgar Preston) Richardson (1902-1985) served as director of the Detroit Institute of Arts (1945-1962) and Winterthur Museum (1963-1966). He was also a board member of the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts from 1966-1977 and, in 1954, co-founded the Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution.
E. P. Richardson was born in 1902 in Glens Falls, New York and died in Philadelphia in 1985. He graduated from Williams College in Massachusetts in 1925 and studied painting at the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts for the three years following graduation. In 1930 he became educational secretary at the Detroit Institute of Arts, was quickly named assistant director in 1933, and served as director from 1945 to 1962. He left Detroit to take the position of director of the Winterthur Museum, where he remained until 1966. Richardson married Constance Coleman in 1931. Born in Berlin, Germany in 1905, Constance Coleman Richardson was an award-winning and widely exhibited realist style painter of American landscapes. She gave up painting in the 1960s and died in 2002.
While at the Detroit Institute of Arts, E. P. Richardson co-founded the Archives of American Art with Lawrence Fleischman, and served as the Archives' first director. Richardson was also art advisor to John D. Rockefeller III for over ten years, editor of Art Quarterly from 1938 to 1967, and a member of various boards, including the Historical Society of Pennsylvania, the Smithsonian Arts Commission, and the National Portrait Gallery. He authored numerous books including ones on artists Washington Allston and Charles Willson Peale, and The Way of Western Art: American Romantic Painting (1939), Painting in America: The Story of Four Hundred and Fifty Years (1956), A Short History of Painting in America (1963), and American Art, an Exhibition of the Collection of Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, 3d (1976).
Conditions Governing Access
Use of original material requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Contact References Services for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Edith Wilkinson first donated a letter to E. P. Richardson from herself in 1957. E.P. Richardson donated papers to the Archives of American Art in 1958 and 1960 and lent materials for microfilming in 1961. Addition material was donated by Constance Richardson in 1985, and by Martha Fleischman in 2003.
Related Materials
Related collections among the holdings of the Archives of American Art include an interview with E.P. Richardson dated February 6, 1978 conducted by Linda Downs; and several miscellaneous manuscripts that include an E.P. Richardson Letter to Rockwell Kent, June 15 1959; E.P. Richardson letters to Lawrence Arthur Fleischman, May 13, 1962 and August 22 1954; and a Yasuo Kunioshi letter to E.P. Richardson, July 25 1948.
Additional E.P. Richardson papers are found at the Detroit Institute of Arts and in the archives of the Henry Francis du Pont Winterthur Museum.
Scope and Contents
The papers of art historian E. P. Richardson measure 28.7 linear feet and date from 1814-1996, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1921-1996. Within the papers are scattered biographical materials; acquisition files for Richardson's personal art collection; professional and personal correspondence with colleagues, art historians and critics, artists, museums, galleries, and dealers; numerous writings, including manuscripts and research files for his published books, articles, and lectures; general research notebooks and files compiled by Richardson on a wide variety of art-related topics and artists; professional and committee files; as well as a smaller amount of Constance C. Richardson's papers.
Biographical materials include certificates, awards, and honorary degrees, membership information, personal and family photographs, a few sketches, and a transcript of an oral history Interview with E.P. Richardson conducted by the National Endowment for the Humanities in 1982.
There are acquisitions files for the Richardsons' personal art collection that invoices, photographs, correspondence with galleries and collectors, appraisals, price lists, and artwork examination forms.
Correspondence is with colleagues, art dealers, collectors, museums and museum curators, foreign scholars, organizations, galleries, artists, art historians and critics, publishers, editors, librarians, friends, and family. Topics regard purchasing art for various collections, consultations about art and collecting including authentications and attributions, publishing, general art history, lectures, and personal matters, among other topics. There is correspondence with the Archives of American Art, Castano Galleries, Lawrence Fleischman, James Thomas Flexner, Alfred V. Frankenstein, George Croce, Walter Heil, Earl Krentzin, Wilmarth Lewis, Russel Lynes, John Francis McDermott, Philadelphia Museum of Art, J. Hall Pleasants, Anna Rutledge, Charles Sellers, Smithsonian Institution, Regina Soria, Victor Spark, William Stevens, Robert Vose, William Woolfenden, and many others. Scattered correspondence with artists is with Isabel Bishop, Louis Bouche, William Bostick, Eve Garrison, Edward Hopper, Irene Jungwirth, Yasuo Kuniyoshi, Hughie Lee-Smith, Reginald Marsh, Gerald Mast, Georgia O'Keeffe, Charles Sheeler, Walt Speck, and John Wedda, among many others. The greatest extent of correspondence is with Andrew Wyeth, Harold Cohn, and Frederick Simper. There is also personal correspondence with family and friends, and between E.P. and Constance Richardson.
E.P. Richardson's prominence as an art historian, writer, and expert on collecting is well documented through his prolific writings. Materials include drafts, notes, typescripts, and outlines for articles, exhibition catalog essays, and lectures. Also found are research files and publishing documentation for Richardson's books, including Washington Allston: A Study of the Romantic Artist in America (1948), Painting in America (1956), Charles Willson Peale and his World (1983), and American Romantic Painting (1944). There are also miscellaneous notes and four diaries. Two of the diaries comment on the social and cultural life of Detroit; the authenticity of paintings; Richardson's reflections on contemporary American painting, thoughts about museums, dealers, artists, and art historians (especially Wilhelm R. Valentiner); and travel.
Notebooks compiled by Richardson on a wide variety art-related topics cover nearly six decades. There are also numerous research files organized Richardson about individual artists and art history. And, the art collector files contain reference materials about art collectors and their collections including Lamont du Pont Copeland, Michael W. Freeman, Nelson Rockefeller, Mr. and Mrs. Joseph Allen, and the Marquis de Somerlous. There are three index card file boxes containing bibliographic data on published books and articles.
Professional and committee files document Richardson's professional and consulting work for the Art Quarterly, Detroit Institute of Arts, National Collection of Fine Arts, the National Portrait Gallery, the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, the John D. Rockefeller III collection, Winterthur Museum, the White House, and the Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
Constance C. Richardson's papers include business and professional correspondence with various institutions, most extensively with the Macbeth Gallery. In addition, there is a smaller amount of personal correspondence, photographs and slides of her artworks, printed materials, two illustrated notebooks on her work, and miscellaneous notes. Also included is Constance's artist palette.
Separated Materials
The Archives of American Art also holds material lent for microfilming (reel D46) including E.P. Richardson's research material on Jeremiah P. Hardy. These materials are housed at the Smithsonian American Art Museum Library and are not described in the collection container inventory.
Existence and Location of Copies
Portions of the collection and material lent for microfilming are available on 35mm microfilm reels 2803, 267, 3470, D10, and D46 at the Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of material described in the container inventory does not reflect the arrangement of the collection on microfilm.
Photographs; Manuscripts; Art -- Collectors and collecting; Painting, American; Art, American; Interviews; Diaries; Detroit (Mich.); Romanticism; Authors -- Michigan -- Detroit; Art -- History -- Study and teaching; Art historians -- United States; Transcripts; Sketches; Lectures; Rutledge, Anna Wells; Simper, Fred, 1914-; McDermott, John Francis, 1902-; Speck, Walter, 1895-; Stevens, William B.; Fredericks, Marshall M., 1908-1998; Castano, Giovanni, 1896-1978; Castano Galleries (Boston, Mass.); Soria, Regina, 1911-; Historical Society of Pennsylvania; Lynes, Russell, 1910-1991; Frankenstein, Alfred V. (Alfred Victor), 1906-1981; Hardy, Jeremiah Pearson, 1800-1889; Pleasants, J. Hall (Jacob Hall), 1873-1957; Garrison, Eve Josephson, 1903-2003; Bishop, Isabel, 1902-1988; Allston, Washington, 1779-1843; Woolfenden, William E. (William Edward), 1918-1995; Ripley, S. Dillon (Sidney Dillon), 1913-2001; Morse, John D., 1906-; Watkins, Franklin Chenault, 1894-1972; Lewis, W. S. (Wilmarth Sheldon), 1895-1979; Marsh, Reginald, 1898-1954; Sheeler, Charles, 1883-1965; Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, 1889-1953; Bostick, William A.; Jungwirth, Irene G. (Irene Gayas), 1913-; Oliver, Andrew, 1906-; Simpson, Corelli C. W.; Andrews, Wayne; Valentiner, Wilhelm Reinhold, 1880-1958; Middeldorf, Ulrich Alexander, 1901-; Spark, Victor D. (Victor David), 1898-1991; Fleischman, Lawrence A. (Lawrence Arthur), 1925-1997; Sellers, Charles Coleman, 1903-; Peale family; Heil, Walter, 1890-1973; Macbeth Gallery; Lee-Smith, Hughie; Bouché, Louis, 1896-1969; Moser, Liselotte, 1906-1983; Archives of American Art; Flexner, James Thomas, 1908-2003; Philadelphia Museum of Art; Vose, Robert C. (Robert Churchill), 1911-1998; Cohn, Harold; Aram, Siegfried F.; Mast, Gerald, 1908-1971; Krentzin, Earl, 1929-; Groce, George C., 1899-; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827; Culver, Charles B. (Charles Beach), 1908-1967; Wedda, John; Boyd, Julian P. (Julian Parks), 1903-; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986; Wyeth, Andrew, 1917-2009; Hopper, Edward, 1882-1967; National Collection of Fine Arts (U.S.); National Portrait Gallery (Smithsonian Institution); Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts; White House (Washington, D.C.); Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979; Rockefeller, John D., 1906-; Detroit Institute of Arts; Henry Francis du Pont Winterthur Museum; Copeland, Lammot du Pont; Freeman, Michael W.; Allen, Joseph
- Biographical Materials, 1924-1985; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 1, 30
  Scope and Contents
  Biographical materials include certificates, awards, and honorary degrees, membership information, address books, personal and family photographs, family business documents such as stock certificates and other financial records, a small volume of newspaper clippings, a few sketches, and a file on travel. Of particular note is a transcript of an oral history Interview with E.P. Richardson conducted by the National Endowment for the Humanities in 1982.
  - Biographies and Obituaries, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1950-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Financial and Business Papers, 1940-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Honorary Doctor of Arts Degree, Wayne University, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Honorary Doctor of Fine Arts Degree, University of Pennsylvania, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Honorary Doctoral Degree, Laval University, 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Honors and Awards, 1947, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Honors and Awards, American Association of Museums, Award for Distinguished Service to Museums, 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Honors and Awards, Artists' Fellowship, Inc., Gari Melchers Gold Medal, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Honors and Awards, Order of Leopold, Belgian Government, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Honors and Awards, Smithson Medal, Smithsonian Institution, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Memberships, 1935, 1960-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Scope and Contents note
    Oversize items housed in Box 30, Folder 1.
  - Names and Addresses, 1940-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Oral History Interviews of Richardson by Marilyn B. Ghausi for National Endowment for the Humanities, Transcripts, 1982-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, 1960, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Poetry and Wedding Clipping, circa 1924-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Sketches, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Travel, circa 1944-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Oversize items from Memberships, Box 1, Folder 12, 1935, 1960-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 1)
    Oversize items from Box 1, Folder 12.
- E.P. Richardson's Personal Art Collection, circa 1930-1996; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 1-2
  Acquisition files for the Richardsons' personal art collection include invoices and paid checks, photographs of artworks, correspondence between the Richardsons and galleries and collectors, appraisals, price lists, and artwork examination forms.
  Arrangement
  Arranged in alphabetical order by artist's surname or, if no name is given, by the genre or title of the artwork.
  - 14th Century, Italian Marriage Coffre, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 15th Century, Flemish, Head of an Angel, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 15th Century, Flemish, Vision of St. Hubert, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 15th Century, Venetian Medal of Frater Mauro Michaelis, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 16th Century, Bronze Chimera, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 16th Century, Bronze Crab and Terracotta Head of Hercules, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 17th Century, Dutch Miniature Chandelier, 1961-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 17th Century, European Drawings, 1937, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 18th Century, Dutch Carved Wooden Fountain, 1945-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 18th Century, Dutch Lead Tobacco Box, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 18th Century, Italian Antique Paintings, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 18th Century, South German or Austrian, Two Figures, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 19th Century, Automaton and Singing Bird, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Allston, Washington, Letter and Pencil Sketch, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Architectural Fantasy, Negative of Canvas, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Benouville, Jean Achile, circa 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bernini, 1957-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bierstadt, Albert, 1971-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Birch, Laurel Hill Cemetery, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Blakelock, Ralph Albert, Landscape with Houses and Boat, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Both, Jan, Landscape, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bracquemond, Felix Henri, Roseaux et Sarcelles, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Burchfield, Farm Landscape, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - C. Dikran Kelekian Ancient Arts, 1964-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Canaletto, Tomb of a Bishop Etching, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Casilear, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Catlin, Osceola, 1957-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Chinese Crystal Dog Seal, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Cole, Thomas, Storm on the Hudson, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - da Cortona, Pietro, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Costa Rica, Horned Owl Effigy Mace Head, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Curran, Charles, Garden at the Cluny Museum, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Curtis, Edward S., 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - D'Arcy Galleries, 1959-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Egyptian, Fragment of a Relief, 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Egyptian, Head of a Hellenistic Ruler of Egypt, 1953-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Furniture, 17th Century Spanish Red Lacquer Cabinet, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Furniture, Biedermeier Cabinet, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Furniture, French Pastry Table, 1970-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Furniture, Italian Walnut Credenza, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Greek Hellenistic Bronze Poseidon, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Greek Hellenistic Terracotta Tondos, 1965-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Greek Terracotta Votive Bust of Dionysos, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Greek Terracottas, 1960, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - van Goyen, Jan, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - van Goyen and de Beyer, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Hopper, Edward, Drawings, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Insurance, circa 1950-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 67-68)
  - Insurance, Jeffrey Fuller Fine Art, Ltd., 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - J.J. Klejman Gallery, 1955-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Jarvis, J.W., Miniature Water Color, 1946-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Johnson, David, View of North Conway, New Hampshire, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Kensett, Long Island Sketch, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Kniep, Christoph Heinrich, 1947-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Loan Catalogs, 1939, 1962-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Maderno, Stefano, Hercules and Antaeus, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Magnasco, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Mayer, Frank B., 1966-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Milanese School, Pietro Bembo Medal, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Notes, circa 1930-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 80-81)
  - Notes, circa 1930-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Notes, Photocopies, circa 1930-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pannini, 1963-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Persian Post-Sassanian, Bronze Vase Handle, 1947-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Artworks, circa 1940-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Richards, William Trost, Tomb of the Slaves Drawing, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Rockefeller, Collection Gifts, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Romanesque Corbel, Head of a Bishop, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Roman Bronze Arm from a Large Statue, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Roman Bronze Bee, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Roman Bronze Head of Boy, 1974-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Roman Bronze Mercury or Apollo, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Roman Imperial Bronze Wing, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Roman Terracotta St. Ambrose, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Rugs, 1971, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Samuel T. Freeman Galleries, Auction Catalogs, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Sandby, Paul, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Sold Artworks, 1968-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Steenwyck the Younge, Hendrik van, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Stradanus, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Thompson, Alfred Wordsworth, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Unknown, Italian Theatre, circa 1930-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Vanni, Francesco, Map of Siena, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Various Invoices and Checks, 1945-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Vedder, Elihu, Arch in a Village Street, circa 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Vedder, Elihu, The Cup of Love, 1974-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Vedder, Elihu, Ideal Head, 1974-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Vedder, Elihu, The Sorceress, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Vedder, Elihu, The Sphinx, 1966-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - van de Velde, Jan, Landscape with Two Peasants, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Waugh, Frederick J., 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Weber, Paul, 1981-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Weenix, G.B., circa 1930-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Weir, Robert Walter, 1957-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - West, Raphael Lamar, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Whittredge, Worthington, 1961-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Wyeth, Andrew, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Zuccero Drawing, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Correspondence, 1926-1988; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 4.6 Linear feet Boxes 2-6
  Series is arranged as 4 subseries based on type of correspondent.
  Missing Title
  3.1: General, 1926-1988
  3.2: With Artists, 1942-1985
  3.3: With Foreign Scholars, 1945-1964
  3.4: Personal, 1930-1986
  Correspondence is with art dealers, collectors, museum curators, museums, artists, art critics, art historians, publishers, editors, librarians, foreign scholars, organizations, friends, and family. Topics regard purchasing art for various collections, consultations about art and collecting including authentications and attributions, publishing, general art history, lectures, and personal matters, among other topics.